# David D'Arcangelo

Director, Massachusetts Office On Disability

## Summary

David D'Arcangelo is Director of the MassachusettsOffice On Disability and is a Malden City Councilor Atlarge.

David is considered one of the Commonwealth's most prolific political activists and was the 2014 Republican nominee for Secretary of State.

David was also Managing Director for Arc Angel Communications and Adjunct Faculty at Suffolk University.

With over 22 years of professional experience, David has been the catalyst for a large number of successful public endeavors including winning political campaigns, corporate turnarounds and non-profit triumphs.

Having served five Governors and as an aide in the State Senate, David is one of only a handful of public servants to have inside working knowledge of both the Executive and Legislative branches of Massachusetts State Government. Appointed by Governor Mitt Romney to the Mass. Commission for the Blind Rehab Council and reapponited by Governor Patrick, David is considered a leading authority on public policy issues regarding disabilities. He has also served in leadership positions for several Boards and Commissions, which has helped to make David one of the most trusted and respected sources for public affairs and civic information.

David's private sector experience is highlighted by the incredible transformations of a companies that were losing money and now, through David's expertise, are turning a profit. A polished public speaker, writer and team player, David has demonstrated strengths in: Writing, Financial Management, Issue Advocacy, Technology Integration, Public Policy, Campaign Management, Team Leadership and Event Organization.

David has an impressive 3-0 record as a Campaign Manager and ran one of the most successful State Senate campaigns in state history. His innovative plan for "Sunsetting Campaign Warchests" has been editorialized and received critical acclaim, as has his Constitutional amendment to alter the Massachusetts Constitutional amendment process.

## Experience

Director for Massachusetts Office On Disability at Commonwealth of Massachusetts

February 2015 - Present

Lead the Massachusetts Office On Disability and our mission of providing full and equal access and opportunities for persons with disabilities in a manner that fosters dignity and self determination.

#### City Councilor At-Large at City of Malden

November 2011 - Present

City Councilor At Large

#### **Managing Director**

January 2006 - January 2015 (9 years 1 month)

Massachusetts Public Relations

Arc Angel Communications is a Public Relations and Marketing Communications Company with headquarters in Malden Massachusetts. Arc Angel specializes in Massachusetts Public Relations and Massachusetts Public Affairs. We produce a variety of public affairs and marketing communications products and solutions based upon many of the most profound public policy issues facing Boston and Massachusetts.

#### Candidate

February 2014 - November 2014 (10 months)

#### **Delegate**

March 1998 - 2014 (16 years 10 months)

Work to restore two-party government to Massachusetts

#### **Adjunct Faculty at Suffolk University**

January 2010 - December 2013 (4 years)

Teaching Professional Communication, CJN - 177 and Social Media, CJN - 389

#### Member, Chairman 2010-2012

January 2005 - December 2013 (9 years)

Member and former Chair of the Massachusetts Commission for the Blind Rehabilitation Council

#### **Election Officer at City of Boston Election Department**

2008 - September 2013 (5 years 9 months)

Oversee election activities

#### **Secretary & Past President**

July 2012 - July 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Malden Rotary Club, which is the oldest continually active service organization in the City of Malden

#### Former Member, Malden Planning Board

January 2002 - January 2008 (6 years 1 month)

Make decisions on Planning and Development cases for the City of Malden

#### **Regional Development Manager**

2006 - 2008 (3 years)

Senior Housing Development

#### **Board Member**

2006 - 2008 (3 years)

Enhance employment opportunities for persons with disabilities

#### **Chief Communication Officer**

January 2002 - December 2006 (5 years)

Direct communications efforts and help run Massachusetts second largest mid-sized bus company

#### **Municipal Affairs & Public Policy Liasion**

1999 - 2003 (5 years)

Manage and coordinate the Massachusetts State Senate with five cities and towns

#### **Municipal Affairs & Public Policy**

1998 - 2002 (5 years)

Served as a liaison between five cities and towns and the 3rd Middlesex District

#### **Municipal Affairs & Public Policy**

1998 - 2002 (5 years)

Direct Communication and outreach efforts, developed and maintained media relationships, create and manage PR, Public Affairs and Marketing collateral

#### Governor's Office, State Senate

1996 - 2002 (7 years)

Serve Governor Cellucci as a Correspondence and Constituent Services Aide

#### Aide

1996 - 1998 (3 years)

Assist with Trade mission preparation

### Education

#### **Suffolk University**

Bachelor of Science, Communications & Journalism, 1988 - 1996

Activities and Societies: Forensics Team, Deabate and Individual Events - National Forensics Association,

Three-time Dean's List recipient

**Suffolk University** 

Bachelor of Science, Communication, 1988 - 1996

**Activities and Societies:** Forensics Team

**Melrose High School** 

High School Diploma, Psychology, 1985 - 1988

# Honors and Awards

Louis B. Connelly Award for Outstanding Communication and Journalism Alumni

# David D'Arcangelo

Director, Massachusetts Office On Disability



Contact David on LinkedIn